Guide to the Laura McPhee River of No Return Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Material, 2003–2008; Series I
  - Negatives, 2003–2008
    - Black-and-white Film Negatives, 2003–2004
      - Images Captured in 2003
        - Negative Numbers 6418 to 6426, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 1957-1965)
        - Negative Numbers 6429 to 6431, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 1966-1968)
        - Negative Numbers 8472 to 8481, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 1969-1978)
        - Negative Numbers 8835 to 8842, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 1979-1986)
        - Negative Numbers 8998 to 9006, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 1987-1995)
      - Images Captured in 2004
        - Negative Numbers 9757 to 9764, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 1996-2003)
      - Images Without Negative Numbers
        - 4-wheeler, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2004)
        - Aspen, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2005)
        - Caution ( Sign ), 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2006)
        - Dead Cow, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2007)
        - Dirt Road, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2008)
        - Flag Reflect, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2009)
        - Herder 1 with Dog, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2010)
        - Herder 2, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2011)
        - Hill, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2012)
        - Pic Reflect, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2013)
        - Sheep Herder 1, 2003–2004 (Box 35, Folder 2014)
- Project Files, 2003–2014; Series II
  Project files include research, correspondence, and print lists as well as preparatory and promotion material related to exhibitions of her images, her book River of No Return, and other works using her images. There is rich documentation surrounding an exhibition at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, in 2006.
  Series II is organized into eight subseries: Research, Correspondence, Print Lists, Solo Exhibitions, Curated Exhibitions and Events, Book Production, Book Promotion, and Uses of Images in Publications.
  - Research, 2003–2005
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Notebook, 2003–2004 (Box 36, Folder 2015)
      Volume includes roughly chronological notes about images captured by McPhee, persons she encountered, sites she visited in and around Sawtooth Valley, Idaho, as well as her reflections on them.
      The volume is partially filled, pages 5 to 87 and 430 of 431 pages as well as lacking pages 1 to 4. It is accompanied by material formerly laid in the volume including a photographic postcard and pressed flowers.
    - Topographic maps, Challis National Forest and Sawtooth National Forest, Idaho, 2003–2005 (Box 36, Folder 2016)
    - Telephone directory, Grouse Creek Unit, Hecla Mining Company, circa 2004 (Box 36, Folder 2017)
    - Idaho Anti-Wolf Coalition, 2004 June (Box 36, Folder 2018)
    - Notes, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 2019-2022)
  - Correspondence, 2003–2012
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Hinds, Thomas M., to Laura McPhee, 2006 July 29 (Box 36, Folder 2023)
    - Humphreys, W. Michael, to Laura McPhee, 2003 June 10 (Box 36, Folder 2024)
    - Matthews, Edward E., to John McPhee and Yolanda Whitman, 2007 July 19 (Box 36, Folder 2025)
    - McPhee, Laura, to W. Michael Humphreys, Candace P. Humphreys, and R. Matthew Humphreys, 2003 July 3 (Box 36, Folder 2026)
    - Neel, Althea "Acey" C., to Laura McPhee, 2006 July (Box 36, Folder 2027)
    - Rohrbach, John, to Laura McPhee, 2008 November 10-2012 January 19 (Box 36, Folder 2028)
  - Print Lists, 2009
    - Exhibit A - List of Images, Existing Large Size Prints, 2009 April 15 (Box 36, Folder 2029)
    - Laura McPhee Idaho Titles, 2003-2005, undated (Box 36, Folder 2030)
    - Manuscript list, undated (Box 36, Folder 2031)
  - Solo Exhibitions, 2005–2013
    Material related to solo exhibitions of images created during the project that includes preparatory and promotional material.
    Organized chronologically under eight headings for the sites of exhibitions: Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Bernard Toale Gallery, Boise Art Museum, Camargo Foundation, Gail Severn Gallery, Gail Gibson Gallery, Southwest School of Art, and Kemper Museum of Contemporary Art.
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 2005–2006
      Preparatory and promotional material related to Laura McPhee: River of No Return, an exhibition at Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, from May 13 to September 17, 2006.
      - Object list, 2005 December 8 (Box 36, Folder 2032)
      - Text panels, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2033)
      - Brochure text, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2034)
      - Available photography, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2035)
      - Brochure, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2036)
      - Poster, 2006 (Box 37 (Oversize), Folder 2067)
      - Poster, 2006 (Box 37 (Oversize), Folder 2068)
      - Press release, 2006 April 10 (Box 36, Folder 2037)
      - Press preview schedule, 2006 May 3 (Box 36, Folder 2038)
      - Exhibition object checklist, 2006 May 25 (Box 36, Folder 2039)
      - Preview, 2006 May-June (Box 36, Folder 2040)
        Membership periodical published by Museum of Fine Arts, Boston that includes an article by William Stover, "Laura McPhee: River of No Return."
      - Presenter packet, 2006 June (Box 36, Folder 2041)
      - Speakers' biographies, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2042)
      - Remarks, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2043)
      - Lecture draft, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2044)
      - Lecture, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2045)
      - Press coverage of exhibition, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 2046-2047)
        Reviews published in Sun Valley Guide and Art on Paper
      - Press coverage of exhibition, 2006 (Box 37 (Oversize), Folder 2069-2076)
    - Bernard Toale Gallery, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 2048)
      Preparatory material related to Two Canyons, Two Years Later, an exhibition at the Bernard Toale Gallery in Boston, Massachusetts, in 2007.
    - Boise Art Museum, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 2049)
      Promotional material related to River of No Return, an exhibition at the Boise Art Museum in Idaho from August 25, 2007, to January 12, 2008.
      - Press coverage of exhibition, 2007 (Box 37 (Oversize), Folder 2077)
        Review published by Idaho Mountain Express.
    - Camargo Foundation, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 2050)
      Press coverage of an exhibition of McPhee's photography at the Hôtel des Roches Blanches in Cassis, France, related to her residency fellowship with the Camargo Foundation in winter and spring 2007, as well as the Le Printemps du Livre de Cassis.
    - Gail Severn Gallery, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 2051)
      Promotional material related to an exhibition Laura McPhee: River of No Return at the Gail Severn Gallery in Ketchum, Idaho, July 1-29, 2007.
      - Press coverage of exhibition, 2007 (Box 37 (Oversize), Folder 2078-2080)
        Reviews published by Idaho Mountain Express and Wood River Journal (Idaho).
    - Gail Gibson Gallery, 2008 (Box 36, Folder 2052)
      Promotional material related to an exhibition Laura McPhee: River of No Return at the Gail Gibson Gallery in Seattle, Washington, February 21 to March 29, 2008.
    - Southwest School of Art, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 2053)
      Promotional material related to an exhibition Laura McPhee: River of No Return at the Russell Hills Rogers Gallery, Southwest School of Art, in San Antonio, Texas, from September 1 to November 20, 2011.
    - Kemper Museum of Contemporary Art, 2013 (Box 36, Folder 2054)
      Promotional material related to an exhibition Laura McPhee: River of No Return at the Kemper Museum of Contemporary Art in Kansas City, Missouri, from May 17 to September 22, 2013.
  - Curated Exhibitions and Events, 2007–2014
    Chiefly promotional material related to curated exhibitions and fundraisers that included of images created during the project as well as events such as lecture series.
    Organized chronologically under seven headings for the sites of exhibitions and events: Museum of Contemporary Art, Shanghai, Montserrat College of Art Gallery, Massachusetts College of Art Design Foundation, Western Washington University, Arts Council of Princeton, Rhode Island School of Design. Museum of Art, and George Eastman House.
    - Museum of Contemporary Art, Shanghai, 2007 (Box 36, Folder 2055)
      Catalog related to a curated exhibition Art in America Now: Three Hundred Years of Innovation initially held at the National Art Museum of China, Beijing, from February 10 to April 5, 2007, and then retitled as Art in America: Now at the Museum of Contemporary Art, Shanghai, May 1 to June 30, 2007. This catalog was likely distributed at the latter site based on the cover title.
    - Montserrat College of Art Gallery, 2010 (Box 36, Folder 2056)
      Promotional material related to a curated exhibition America Now at the Montserrat College of Art Gallery in Beverly, Massachusetts, from February 5 to April 10, 2010.
    - Massachusetts College of Art Design Foundation, 2010 (Box 36, Folder 2057)
      Promotional material related to the 21st Annual Benefit Art Auction, a fundraiser for the Massachusetts College of Art Design Foundation, held at the David and Sandra Bakalar Gallery and the Stephen D. Paine Gallery at the Massachusetts College of Art and Design in Boston, Massachusetts, on April 10, 2010.
    - Western Washington University, 2010–2011 (Box 36, Folder 2058)
      Promotional material related to a curated exhibition, Critical Messages: Contemporary Northwest Artists on the Environment, held at the Western Gallery, Western Washington University, Bellingham, from April 12 to May 29, 2010. The exhibition also traveled to the Hallie Ford Museum of Art at Willamette University in Salem, Oregon, August 28 to November 7, 2010, and the Boise Art Museum in Idaho from December 18, 2010, to April 11, 2011.
    - Arts Council of Princeton, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 2059)
      Promotional material related to an exhibition, Between You and Me: An Exhibition of Photographic Portraiture, sponsored by the Arts Council of Princeton at the Paul Robeson Center for the Arts in Princeton, New Jersey, from March 5 to April 16, 2011.
    - Rhode Island School of Design. Museum of Art, 2012–2013 (Box 36, Folder 2060)
      Promotional material related to a group exhibition America in View: Landscape Photography 1865 to Now held at the Museum of Art, Rhode Island School of Design, Providence, from September 21, 2012, to January 13, 2013.
    - George Eastman House, 2014 (Box 36, Folder 2061)
      Promotional material related to a photography lecture series in 2014, Wish You Were Here, sponsored by the George Eastman House in Rochester, New York. McPhee delivered her lecture, "Laura McPhee -- The Elusive Nature of Place," on December 4, 2014.
  - Book Production, 2008–2009
    Material created in the production of Laura McPhee, River of No Return (New Haven, Connecticut: Yale University Press, 2009).
    - Mock-up, spiral binding, 2008 (Box 38)
    - Titles and layout for book dummy, 2008 February 14 (Box 36, Folder 2062)
    - Layout of print signatures, 2008 (Box 37 (Oversize), Folder 2081)
    - Galley, sprial binding, 2008 (Box 39)
    - Galley, unbound signatures, 2008 (Box 40)
    - Galley, case binding and book jacket, 2008 (Box 41)
  - Book Promotion, 2008–2009
    Promotional material related to Laura McPhee, River of No Return (New Haven, Connecticut: Yale University Press, 2009) as well as book reviews of it.
    - Yale University Press catalogue, 2008 August-2009 February (Box 36, Folder 2063)
    - Book reviews, 2009 (Box 36, Folder 2064)
      Includes reviews published by Ag: The International Journal of Photographic Art & Practice, Harper's Bazaar, Orion, Photoicon, and Times-News (Twin Falls, Idaho).
  - Uses of Images in Publications, 2010–2011
    Documentation of images from the project used in publications created by others.
    - Colin Cheney, Here Be Monsters: Poems (Athens, Georgia: University of Georgia Press), book cover, 2010 (Box 36, Folder 2065)
    - Orion magazine, cover, 2011 March-April (Box 36, Folder 2066)